# Sai Harika Sudula







Well-qualified software engineer familiar with knowledge of backend and frontend development requirements. Collaborative team player with good technical abilities offering nearly 4 years of related experience. Open to opportunities to learn and gain expertise in new skills.

### Personal Info

### Mobile:

+91 73829 85829

#### Email:

saiharika27@gmail.com

#### Address:

Bangalore, India

#### LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/saiharikasudula

### Skills

### **Programming:**

C, Java, Python, Golang, PHP OOPs, Data Structures, Algorithms, Machine Learning, Hadoop, Spark, GraphQL

#### UI/UX:

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, AdobeXD, Canva, Figma

### **Databases:**

MSSQL, Postgresql, Oracle

### **Operating Systems:**

Windows, Linux

### Tools:

AWS, IntelliJ IDEA, JupyterLabs, SonarQube, VCS, Jenkins, Jira

### Interests

Design, Psychology, Sports, Music, Poetry, Creative Writing, Public Speaking

# Languages

English, Hindi, Telugu(native)

## Education

# National Institute of Technology Bhopal

Bachelors in Technology Computer Science and Engineering 2015 - 2019 7.4 CGPA

# Work Experience

### Amazon India, Bangalore

Software Development Engineer - Seller & Fulfillment Tech | Oct 2022 - Present

- Designing solutions and building various features to support Vendor Central and Seller Central applications that handle operations for Fulfillment by Amazon Inbound processes aiding sellers from different marketplaces inbound their products to Amazon warehouses.
- Participating in testing customer journey of various feature workflows for feedback cycles.
- Taking operational responsibility by handling the incoming trouble tickets during oncall rotation.

### Barclays Global Service Center, Pune

Full Stack Developer - Development Services | Nov 2020 - Sep 2022

- Developing products that enable data-driven decision-making culture in engineering teams to optimize Change Delivery and Software Delivery at all levels in the organization through predictive analysis.
- Building and optimizing data ingestion jobs in Python to avail new metrics for Developer Experience Insights dashboards.
- React UI development of Insights Dashboards with knowledge of CI/CD pipeline, version control tools, and DevOps practices.
- Usability Testing and Unit Testing on React and GraphQL projects using frameworks like jest, enzyme, chai, mocha.
- Taking operational responsibility for the services owned by the team potentially including taking part in an on-call rotation.

### IC Agile Authorised Instructor | June 2021 - July 2022

• Running monthly Agile Training Classroom Cohorts for Barclays employees.

### Graduate Analyst - Data Platform Services | July 2019 - Oct 2020

- Delivered changes as per business requirements for Advocacy Complaints MI system in order to address and reduce user complaints. Resolved issues regarding integrity of data flow into warehouses
- Implemented optimised framework procedures for four source systems to improve streamline data collection and analysis, resulting in higher consistency for MI reporting system.
- Worked on ETL data acquisition of third-party payment services introduced in Barclays mobile banking apps as part of integration with Zapp platform.

## **Appointy India, Bhopal**

### Product Development Intern | May 2018 - July 2018

- Developed an online fitness and massage session booking system for Google global offices from design conceptualisation to client delivery using Golang.
- Conducted functional testing over the course of product development lifecycle.

# **Participations**

- Part of Barclays Women's Football Team.
- President for Barclays Pune Toastmasters Club, served as VPPR in the past.
- Worked on a pilot project as part of the 'Tech in Vogue' program administered by Women in Technology(WiT), Barclays.
- BUK Tech India Developer Bootcamp: led a team of 6 people during the program and worked on a hands-on project to develop and deploy an API using Jenkins.
- CSR Activity: volunteered in career sharing, resume editing, mock interview sessions for University students by Make A Difference and many fundraiser activities.